apnacircle.com 2016-06-10

# Privacy Policy | Fish

#### Effective: January 1, 2010

This Privacy Policy (“ **Policy”** ) describes the privacy practices applicable to the Fish & Richardson P.C. website located at www.fr.com, including how personal information about you may be obtained, used, shared, and disclosed by us. This Policy also describes how you can opt out of some uses of personal information.

### I. INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Personal information is information through which you can be identified, such as your name, postal address, email address, and telephone number. When you visit our site, we do not collect personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide personal information to us (for example, by sending us an email or registering for a newsletter or other event). If you provide personal information to us, we might receive additional information about you from other sources and combine that additional information with the personal information you provided.

Non-personal information is information about you or your activities through which you cannot be personally identified. When you visit our site, we may collect non-personal information, such as the type of browser and operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider, which pages you visit on our site and how long you spend on each page, and the unique number assigned to your server or Internet connection. We may use this information for a variety of purposes, including to monitor use of and improve our site as well as for internal analysis.

**Cookies** are small files that contain information sent by a website that is saved on your computer’s hard drive. When you visit our site, we may place a cookie on your computer to help us recognize and serve you better when you return. You may delete cookies from your computer or set your browser to reject cookies. However, doing so may limit some functionalities of our site.

### II. HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We may use your personal and non-personal information for our own marketing and non-marketing purposes. For example, we may use personal information to respond to your email or telephone inquiries or to advise you of upcoming events, newsletters, or legal developments. In addition, we may add your personal information to our databases, including subscriber and contact lists.

Your personal and non-personal information may be shared for any purpose among any of the offices of Fish & Richardson P.C., including those in the United States and Europe. When you submit personal information to us through our site, you understand and consent to the transfer of your personal information across national borders and to the storage and processing of your information in a country that may not provide the same level of privacy protection that your country provides.

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. Your personal information may be shared with unrelated third parties, including contractors that provide services to us. For example, we may provide your personal information to third parties that assist with the operation or maintenance of our site or that we may hire to deliver newsletters or other materials to you. When we provide personal information to third parties, we require those parties to exercise reasonable care to protect your personal information, and we restrict the use of your personal information to the purposes for which it was provided to them. We may use non-personal information for a variety of purposes, including statistical or demographic analysis and improvements in the design and content of our site.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information if we believe that our site is being used to commit unlawful acts; if disclosure of your personal information is required to comply with applicable laws or regulations or with a court or administrative order, or will help to enforce any applicable terms of use; to protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; or to protect the safety and security of our site or third parties.

### III. MAKING CHANGES TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION 

Each of our marketing emails includes an automated way for you to opt out (unsubscribe) from that particular communication or from all marketing emails sent by Fish & Richardson. To opt out, please follow the instructions on the email you receive. Or you may email us at info@fr.com to update your preferences. It may take about 30 days for any changes to your personal profile to take effect.

### IV. SECURITY

Although we employ security measures that we believe are reasonably appropriate to protect your personal information, we do not guarantee that our security precautions will protect against the loss or misuse of your personal information. Similarly, we cannot guarantee the privacy of personal information you transmit over the Internet or that may be collected in transit by others, including contractors that provide services to us.

### V. OTHER WEBSITES AND CO-SPONSORED EVENTS 

Our site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the information collection or privacy practices of other websites. You should consult privacy policies of other sites before you visit those sites or provide any personal information to those sites. We may provide information at our site about programs and events that are sponsored by or co-sponsored by other firms or organizations. If you register for any of these events, we may have no control over the third-party sponsors’ use of your personal information.

### VI. REVISIONS TO THIS POLICY

We reserve the right to revise this Policy at any time without notice. Please review this Policy periodically for changes.

### VII. QUESTIONS

If you have any questions regarding this Policy, or if you wish to opt out of the use of your personal data by Fish & Richardson P.C., you may contact us by email at [info@fr.com](mailto:info@fr.com?subject=Privacy%20policy) or write to us at the address below:

Elizabeth Cerasuolo  
Fish & Richardson P.C.  
One Marina Park Drive  
Boston, MA 02110-1878  
617-542-5070

Please note that it will take some time for your updated preferences to take effect.
